WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Thank God.
Yes. Thank God.
And you.
How do we speak to him?
Normally.
How do you think you speak to him?
Do we pretend prison never happened?
I don't think that'll be necessary.
Welcome back, Mr Bates.
I've waited a long time to say that.
Thank you, Mr Carson.
Too long.
Give us your coat.
Oh, Mrs Patmore, can you find
something for Mr Bates to eat?
I certainly can. Daisy! Ivy!
Stir your stumps!
Who's Ivy?
The new kitchen maid.
Thomas. Still here, I see.
Mr Barrow, now, Mr Bates.
And, yes, I'm still here.
And busy as a bee.
There have been some changes
since er... since you've been away.
You will have heard
about Lady Sybil.
Yes, I've heard.
Anna took a letter from me
to her Ladyship.
There we are.
Thank you, Mrs Patmore.
Can we all have one of those?
Welcome back, Mr Bates.
Thank you, Daisy.
Something nice?
The editor's written back,
repeating his offer.
He asks if I'm ever in London.
Why not? You could see Rosamund
and buy some new clothes.
He only wants to persuade you
to write for his horrible paper.
Still, I think I will go.
It seems rude not to in a way and
I haven't been to London for ages.
Excuse me.
Please don't encourage her.
I think it's a good idea.
I gather you've trapped
poor old Jarvis into a meeting.
It won't take long.
But he is the agent
and there are things we must get
started on, if you agree.
Well, I'm glad you still think
my agreement has a part to play.
Are you sure you wouldn't rather
just cut and run, like me?
Bates! My dear fellow!
I didn't know you were here already!
They let you out at dawn.
Thank you for sending
Anna in the car.
Oh, nonsense.
Where have they put you?
In my old room, m'lord.
That won't do.
I'll ask Jarvis how far they've got
with finding a cottage. Thank you.
About Thomas?
I'll sort it out, Bates. I promise.
But in the meantime you just rest.
Stay in bed. Read books.
But you didn't walk out of my
luncheon when Robert asked you to.
Well, that luncheon was
to support Cora in her grief.
It did not seem appropriate
to let the whole thing
end in chaos and a quarrel.
So you don't think I should have
given Ethel a second chance?
I do not criticise your motives,
but did you really consider?
Ethel is notorious in the village.
I don't think so.
I know so.
You have surrounded this house
with a miasma of scandal
and touched all of us
by association.
I think one must fight
for one's beliefs.
And is poor Ethel to be the cudgel
by which you fight your foes?
Ah, Ethel.
I was just telling Lady Grantham
how your cooking has come on.
I'm studying, m'lady. These days,
a working woman must have a skill.
But you seem to have so many.
I don't see how you can
just sack him.
He's done nothing wrong.
He can't have expected to stay
my valet once Bates was released.
Ask Carson. He'll have some ideas.
Poor little girl.
Has Branson said anything
more about moving out?
How can he move before he's found
a job? How can you want him to?
He's our responsibility now,
Robert - he and the baby.
We owe that to Sybil.
I must get on. I've got this
meeting with Jarvis and Matthew.
Have you got any plans, Mr Bates?
It's rather early to say. His
lordship suggested I have a rest.
I expect you'll be looking
for something to do, Mr Barrow.
Now that Mr Bates is back.
They're showing a film tonight
in the village hall. Way Down East.
It's about a woman
who survives in the wilderness
through her own wits and courage.
Blimey. They've stolen my story!
Lillian Gish is in it.
I like her.
There's a late showing tonight
at half past ten,
for the local servants.
What about it?
Are you going Jimmy?
Sounds a bit soppy, to be honest.
Well, I'm not going with
Alfred on my own.
My mum wouldn't like it.
She would not and nor would I.
You may go if Madge
or Alice will go with you.
But not otherwise.
All right. If Mrs Patmore agrees.
Straight there and back mind.
This means the overhaul of every part
of the estate we hold in hand
and some large new parcels
in addition.
All in an instant.
But don't you see?
If we invest in new machinery,
new methods and new techniques,
the whole estate must benefit by it.
And as for taking new lands in hand,
we won't be running it separately.
We'll find another use
for some of the farmhouses...
This is ridiculous! Downton has
existed for hundreds of years
in perfect harmony.
We have worked
with the farmers as partners.
Now you want to blow it all
to smithereens!
Of course I don't, but -
If I may, my Lord?
Mr Crawley, you are very new
to our way of life here.
I beg your pardon!
There's no point biting Jarvis's
head off. You are new to it.
Must I remind you of the state
the place was in a few months ago?
That was nothing to do
with the way we run it!
The money was lost
in a bad investment.
And you've been bailing the place
out with Cora's fortune.
You have been for years.
Downton must be self-supporting if
it's to have a chance of survival!
Well, you've given us plenty to
think about. Hasn't he, Mr Jarvis?
He has indeed, Lord Grantham.
Why would I persuade your father
otherwise when I agree with him?
How can you say that when you keep
telling me to find something to do?
I meant run a local charity
or paint watercolours or something.
Well, I'm going to London
to see the editor tomorrow
and if I like him
then I'm going to say yes.
I don't want to fall out with Papa,
but I don't want to be invisible
either.
I've had enough of it.
Very well. I'm coming up tonight.
I'll see what I can do.
But I want a favour in return.
Ethel? What's the matter?
I had rather a nasty encounter
in the village, that's all.
What sort of encounter?
Mrs Bakewell refused to serve me.
In the end her husband did,
but it wasn't very nice.
We shall take our business
elsewhere.
There's no need for that, Ma'am.
I'm used to it.
You shouldn't have to be.
Are you all set for this evening?
If you mean have I allowed Ivy to go
out when it's not her half day,
I have, but why,
I could not tell you.
Bring them all home safe.
If that's Bechamel, why don't
you use parsley or mace?
I do. But I boil it
in the milk beforehand.
I made it last night.
Oh, leave her alone, you big ninnie.
There's nothing wrong
with a man who can cook.
Some say the best cooks
in the world are men.
And do we think this sad beanpole
will be the best cook in the world?
Why do you always feel the need
to be so unpleasant, James?
What's Alfred ever done to you?
Er... you can take in the fish
and meat tonight.
James can follow with the sauce.
But I should be the First Footman.
Of course you should.
Listen to her!
You're taller than him!
You've been here longer than him!
Why are you taking her to the
pictures when she talks like that?
Well, I've got the tickets now,
so...
Don't get up.
How's the Christening going?
It's all arranged with
the Catholic Church in Ripon.
Weren't you going to tell us?
You and Matthew?
I didn't think the others
would want to know.
Please give them a chance
to behave properly.
I wondered if you'd be a Godmother?
Am I allowed to be?
As long as at least one of them
is Catholic
and my brother's coming over.
He'll stay in the village.
No, he won't. He'll stay here.
He's a bit of a rough diamond.
I'm very fond of diamonds.
I still can't believe I'm here.
I keep pinching myself.
Believe.
Which one would be ours?
Well, they won't move Mr Chirk
or the Tripps,
but Mrs Bow wants to live in
the village, so we might get hers.
None of which solves the problem
of what I'm going to do.
Your job, of course. They'll have
to give Thomas his notice.
Mr Barrow.
Mr 'Stick-It-Up-Your-Jumper'.
He'll have to go.
Revenge is sweet.
Look at him.
He can't even balance it.
Oh, leave him alone. Up you go.
It's a flipping insult.
Just cos he's ten foot tall.
You're right.
I've got a good mind to...
Don't do anything you'll regret.
These things can be managed,
but not by losing your temper.
You make a cosy couple,
I must say.
I don't think so.
It's not what I've heard.
Alfred says he's always going on
about you.
Silly sloppy stuff.
Alfred's sick and tired of it
and no wonder.
Well, he's making it up.
Have it you own way.
Right, don't put them like that.
They've got to be able
to get hold of them.
That's why I've asked
Mr Murray to come up.
You've asked Murray to come here
without consulting me?
I felt I wasn't explaining things
well and I know he can.
Oh, lovely. What a treat.
Oh my, your ladyship!
No, no fuss, no fuss.
Just scrape me down
and get me a spare napkin.
I'll take that.
I saw your cook in the village
today, Isobel. She seemed upset.
Yes. Mrs Bakewell was rather unkind.
It seems a pity that even
in this pretty little village,
people can be so unforgiving.
Some people are unforgiving,
others are insensitive.
What time do you leave in
the morning?
I thought I'd get the ten o'clock.
I'm meeting him for tea.
You're not encouraging this?
She hasn't agreed to anything yet.
Oh, Mama, talk to her. Talk to all
of them. Say something sensible.
Yes. Let's hear how a woman's
place is in the home.
I do think a woman's place
is eventually in the home,
but I see no harm in her having
some fun before she gets there.
Oh, Granny! Thank you!
Have you changed your pills?
And another thing. I mean,
Edith isn't getting any younger.
Perhaps she isn't cut out
for domestic life.
How are your plans proceeding, Tom?
I was telling Lady Grantham.
My brother has a garage
in Liverpool.
He's asked me to go in with him.
The brother who's coming to stay?
Yes. Kieran.
Why is he coming here?
For the Christening.
How did he rearrange the spoons?
Right on the edge of my plate.
I'm not saying it was deliberate.
I hope you're not,
cos I was trying to help.
Well, I think Alfred can manage
without your help in future, James.
And next time, will you wait to be
asked before you take charge?
Are you still here?
Perhaps Alfred no longer wants
to go to the pictures.
He may want to ponder
his mistakes instead.
Of course they're going.
Are we?
Yes, you can go.
I will not withdraw my permission.
But as you walk,
you might contemplate what it is
to waste a chance when it is given.
I suppose you never wasted a chance.
Well, if I did, I learnt from it
and that's all I am asking from him.
That and some ritual humiliation.
You shouldn't have rung Murray
without telling Papa.
You berate me for not wanting
to take responsibility
and now you tell me off
for doing just that.
You can't have it both ways.
I can if I want to.
What's the matter?
Do you think I should see someone?
What? If there's anything wrong
then it's obviously my fault.
You know what they told us
when I was wounded.
But they were wrong. They said so.
I wonder.
Darling, please don't worry.
I'm sure there's nothing wrong.
That's the point. We're not sure.
It was OK, but I prefer
English films with English stars.
They seem more real somehow.
I like the American actors.
They've got more you-know-what.
Oh, and how about Ivy Close
in The Worldlings?
She makes Lilian Gish look like
a village school ma'am.
Ivy Close.
It's funny to think of a film star
having your own name.
There aren't any with my name.
No, but there's a King.
The one who burnt the cakes.
Well, I hope I won't be burning
any of my cakes in future.
Where is everyone?
They've gone to bed.
Except for the picture-goers.
They're not back.
If I'd thrown a bucket of slop
in the old lady's lap,
I wouldn't be allowed
to go to the flicks.
What are you saying?
Mr Carson doesn't like me.
No matter what Alfred does,
he still prefers him.
It's not bloody fair.
Well, I love you.
Well, if you do, you're on your own.
I'm sure I'm not.
What about your family?
Where are you from?
I don't have any family,
not really. Cousins. You know.
No-one else.
And your mum and dad?
Dead. My dad was killed in the war
and my mother died of the flu.
I haven't any brothers
and sisters, so here we are.
All on me ownsome.
You must get lonely.
Meaning?
I know what it's like, that's all.
Funny. We're quite a pair.
We both like to look very sure
of ourselves,
but we're not so sure underneath,
are we?
Still you've no need to worry.
Mr Carson may prefer Alfred,
but nobody else does.
Don't they? I wonder.
Sometimes I think
it's just Jimmy Contra Mundi.
Is that Latin? I should try and tell
Mr Carson - make up some points.
Never mind Latin,
I need a magic spell.
Good night.
He's a funny one, isn't he?
You can't pull the wool
over my eyes.
I know what's going on.
You're quite wrong, Miss O'Brien.
He's a proper little ladies' man.
If that's how you want to play it.
What are you going on about?!
There's no need to bark.
I only know what Alfred tells me.
Well, if he says Jimmy's
interested in me, he's lying.
Would he?
Is it supposed to be a secret?
Oh, you are daft!
Oh, Ivy, I love to be out
with you like this.
I wish we could make it
a regular thing.
I can't. I wouldn't want you
to get the wrong idea.
Look, I'm sorry,
but Jimmy's just not interested.
I hate to hurt your feelings
like that, but he's not.
You don't know that.
He flirts with me. He does.
If you knew he wasn't interested,
would that make a difference?
I'd have to hear it from his lips.
Sorry to wake you, Jimmy, but...
Oh, my... Get off!
Just get the bloody hell off me!
Alfred, it's not what you think.
Don't do that. Please.
Alfred doesn't matter.
No-one will believe a word
he says. He's nothing.
What are you doing?
Why are you in here?
Because of what you said.
Because of all there is between us.
There's nothing between us!
Except my fist if you don't get out!
And if you tell any...
But what about the things you said?
I said nothing except
get out. Go on! Get out, Thomas!
What is going on?
Nothing, Mr Carson.
Jimmy, er... James had a nightmare.
He's fine, now.
What is it? What's going on?
James? What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Alfred?
Ask Mr Barrow.
It's nothing. Really.
It doesn't seem like nothing.
Ivy? Never mind the toast, you look
very tasty yourself, this morning.
What did you say?
Can't a red-blooded man
compliment a pretty girl?
Not at breakfast for Heaven's sake!
Alfred, what's happened?
Not now.
Well, if there is anything
I ought to know,
I hope I hear about it
before the end of the day.
This really has been so interesting.
I hope this means
you're persuadable, Lady Edith?
I'll think about it, I promise.
I just felt I had to meet you
and see what it would be like.
I assume your father disapproves.
Well, it's the business of
parents to worry, isn't it?
No, all sorts of toffs are writing
for magazines nowadays.
Some of them even advertise face
creams, cigarettes and the rest.
I'm afraid Papa would not
find that reassuring.
In fact, if he were here
he'd probably just shout, 'Run!'
Will you please make up your own
mind without his advice?
I'll have to think about that too.
Are you going back
to Yorkshire tonight?
No. I'm staying with my aunt.
I've got to look in to the offices
of The Lady while I'm here.
Not to write for them, I trust?
Oh, no. It's just something
I promised to do for my grandmother.
The Lady? That's Covent Garden?
Here's an idea.
Let's er, let's have lunch
tomorrow at Rules.
If you accept the job
we'll celebrate.
If it's a no, I'll drown my sorrows.
How's that?
You seem nervous today, Barrow.
We will get things sorted out.
We won't leave you in the lurch.
I'd be grateful if you could let me
know when you've made a decision.
I'll talk things through
with Carson
and we'll see what we can
come up with.
It makes no sense to retain
this bit as a separate section.
No sense at all.
But of course Jarvis won't see that
because he hates change.
Just try to carry Papa
with you. That's all I ask.
He'll be with me in the end because
this is the only way forward
and at some point
he's going to see that.
Some point in the near
future I hope.
What's the matter with you both? You
were in a dream all through dinner.
Nothing's the matter!
Does Mr Murray
want luncheon tomorrow?
No. He's in York all morning.
He'll come up here afterwards.
Followed by Tom's brother
for dinner.
So it promises to be
a day of contrast.
God in heaven.
What do you think, Tom?
I agree with Matthew.
The estate can offer proper
compensation to the tenants now
while the money's there.
But if we miss this chance
it may not come again.
So says the Marxist.
If you don't mind me saying so,
you have a narrow view of socialism.
You seem to have a very broad
interpretation of it.
Now, now, children.
If Branson is watering down
his revolutionary fervour,
let us give thanks.
Tom.
Do you know anything about farming,
Tom?
A little. My grandfather
was a sheep farmer in Ireland.
Why do you keep giving me funny
looks? I'm not.
What's going on?
Have you both been up to
something I don't know about?
Not both of us.
Are you awake?
I can't seem to get
to sleep. I don't know why.
Could you credit Matthew summoning
Murray without my permission?
You keep telling everyone
Downton's a Dual Monarchy now.
I never realised you didn't mean it.
So, you're against me over Matthew,
the Christening and Edith.
Robert...
even your mother spoke up
for Edith. Think of that.
A facer, I admit.
She'll have had some reason
of her own, of course.
Is she really so Machiavellian?
Yes.
I was afraid you'd stood me up.
I'm so sorry.
It took much longer than I thought.
What was it about?
Oh, just family stuff.
An errand for my grandmother.
Are you very family minded?
Well, when you live at home
with your parents, you're still
in the middle of all of it.
I saw a picture in the paper
of your elder sister's wedding.
She looked glamorous.
People say so.
Am I allowed to say I'm rather
pleased you're not married?
I'm a little less pleased.
Oh, dear. It sounds like
you're hiding a romantic secret.
Not too romantic.
A little while ago,
I was jilted at the altar.
Which wasn't much fun.
Oh dear, I am sorry.
Oh, please don't be.
It's a relief to be reminded
I'm not an object of pity
to the entire world.
I've clearly put my foot in it,
and now you'll turn the job down.
Please don't.
I won't.
Not if you don't want me to.
Ah.
Surely, Lord Grantham,
you don't question Mr Crawley's goal
of making the estate
self-sufficient? No.
But I question his plans
for the employees and tenants
in order to achieve it.
Can't we allow things
to evolve more gently,
as we did in the past?
The past is not much of a model.
The third Earl nearly went bankrupt,
the fourth only saved the estate
by dying
and what would you all have done
in the '90s
without Lady Grantham's money?
I say, Murray. When I asked you
to say what you think,
I didn't mean to be taken literally.
Must we talk in this way?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
Thanks to Mr Swire
we have another chance,
but we have to change our ways.
All I'm talking about is investment,
increasing productivity
and reducing waste.
Waste?!
Yes. The estate has been run
very wastefully for many years.
I won't listen to this!
Now, come on, Jarvis.
If I can listen to it, so can you.
No, Lord Grantham, I can't!
Am I to stand here,
after 40 years of loyal service,
to be accused of malfeasance
and corruption!
Nothing of the sort!
My dear chap. Think for a moment.
We must both see things
have to move forward.
My goal is to find the way
of least disruption.
Won't you stay and help
me with that?
My Lord, will you give me
a good reference?
Yes, of course I will.
Mr Jarvis, if I have offended you,
then I offer my sincerest apologies.
I am the old broom, Mr Crawley.
You are the new.
I wish you luck with your sweeping.
M'lord.
Mr Carson, you'd better come.
May I help you?
This is Mr Branson's brother.
Can we fetch Mr Branson, sir?
I've already sent Alfred.
Here they are now.
Kieran? What are you doing
down here? Come upstairs.
I don't fancy it. Can I not stay
put and have my dinner down here?
But we're all so looking forward
to meeting you, Mr Branson.
If you come with us, you can see
your room and get changed.
If you want to. And what would I
change into? A pumpkin?
Come on, Tommy.
Come and eat down here.
They seem like a nice lot.
What's the matter?
Are you too grand for them now?
They know that I'm not,
but my mother-in-law has been
kind enough to invite you to stay
and dine.
And I'll not let you
snub her. Now, get a move on.
I know. You always said he would
bring shame on this house.
No, Mrs Hughes.
For once, I will hold my tongue.
I thought Mr Branson's respect for
her ladyship's invitation exemplary.
Well. 'Mr' Branson's done
something right, for a change.
Miracles can happen.
How was it?
Pretty bad. Jarvis has resigned.
What?
He's gone
and I'm going to have to make it
all work or I've had it.
Come here.
You'll make me untidy.
Good.
You see, I know it's right, Mary.
I believe I can make Downton safe
for our children,
if we ever have any.
But I can only do it
if you're with me.
But what about Papa? I do love him.
Love him by all means,
but believe in me.
There. Will that convince you?
Convince me again.
And don't say,
'If we ever have any.'
Because we will.
But it's been a while now.
What if Mr Carson finds out you knew
all along and you never told him?
How will that look?
Surely it's for Jimmy to tell?
Supposing he's in on it?
No. He started yelling
at Thomas as soon as I walked in.
Yes, I'm sure he did.
As soon as you walked in.
What if you hadn't walked in?
I'm sorry, Alfred. Mr Carson won't
tolerate these sort of shenanigans
and he'll be furious if he finds out
you knew and said nothing.
You need to speak up.
For your own good.
And what exactly does this business
consist of?
Automobile refurbishment.
He means car repairs.
I see. And you would live nearby?
We've rooms over the garage.
There's a bit of a park
not too far away.
Well, that's something.
I remember an evening
rather like this.
We were travelling back
from Scotland to London
when the train was suddenly engulfed
by a blizzard
and we spent the night in a
tradesmen's hotel in Middlesbrough.
So who's coming to the Christening?
All of us, I expect.
Granny? Well, yes.
If Branson... Tom wants me to.
I would be honoured.
Robert, are you coming?
Tom doesn't want me there
and I wouldn't know what to do.
All that crossing
and bobbing up and down.
I went to a Mass once in Rome, it
was more like a gymnastic display.
I would like you
to be there very much.
Why? What difference would it make?
All I know is Sybil
would want you there.
She loved you with all her heart
and she would want you there.
Will you argue with that?
Not if you think it's so important.
How did you get on in London?
Well, as a matter of fact,
I've got an announcement to make.
Now is as good a time as any.
Listen, everyone.
You have a journalist in the family.
Since we have a country solicitor
and a car mechanic,
it's only a matter of time.
How was the editor in the end?
Oh, nice, very nice.
So you're ready to speak out?
I think you're right and I must.
Good. He has broken all
the fundamental laws of God and man.
Report him as you should and then
stand back and enjoy his fall.
I don't understand.
You've placed an advertisement
in a magazine,
to find a job for my housekeeper?
I knew you'd be against it.
Well, how would you feel if I found
other work for your cook or butler?
Granny feels that for Ethel's sake
she should move elsewhere.
Oh, nonsense. She couldn't
give tuppence about Ethel
or anyone like her!
You've been reading those
Communist newspapers again.
I don't suppose there's any beer?
Haven't you had enough?
Of course we have beer.
We must have some somewhere. Carson?
I believe so, m'lady. I'll fetch it.
What's the betting we'll have
a chorus of Molly Malone
before we finish? You're the one
pushing Tom into his brother's arms.
This is not what Sybil wanted
for him. She told me.
Oh, Carson. Would you ask Mrs Hughes
to meet me in the hall, please?
Very good, m'lady. I'll bring
the beer in a moment, sir.
It isn't so bad here, after all.
I don't know.
She just asked if you could go up.
I suppose I'll have to.
What's this?
They said we could go.
They'll ring when they need the car.
Mr Carson, might I have a word?
Well, I have to take this up.
Oh, very well then. Come with me.
Mrs Hughes, you have always
taken an interest in Ethel.
Do you think I'm wrong?
No.
While Ethel is in this village
she is doomed to be lonely.
But if, as her ladyship suggests, she
can get a job far away from here...
She's not a bad cook now
and with a respectable reference,
which of course you can give her...
I can't get over how you've planned
all this without a word to me.
Well, I knew you wouldn't agree.
I know how you hate facing facts.
I resent that. I'm sorry, but I do.
Mrs Crawley, I hope you don't see
me as an intolerant person.
No.
Because I agree with her ladyship.
In a new place,
where she can start again,
Ethel has far more chance
of happiness
than in re-enacting her own version
of The Scarlet Letter in Downton.
What is The Scarlet Letter?
A novel. By Nathaniel Hawthorne.
It sounds most unsuitable.
I'll talk to Ethel.
I don't understand what you're
saying. Thomas was doing what?
That's what I saw, Mr Carson.
And what was James doing?
I think he was asleep,
because he just woke
and he got very angry...
As he should have been, by God.
My auntie says he might have been
faking because I walked in,
but it didn't look fake to me.
Well, we can always rely on your
aunt to take the ungenerous view.
You will not speak of this
to anyone. Is that clear?
I don't want to hear the subject
even mentioned
in the Servants' Hall.
Very good, Mr Carson.
The world can be a shocking place,
Alfred,
but you are a man now and you must
learn to take it on the chin.
Beg pardon, Ma'am. I was miles away.
That's all right.
I just wanted to let you
know that I was back.
Would you like some tea?
No, thank you.
I'm going straight to bed.
Ethel...
are you happy?
Well, I... I suppose I'm happy
compared to what I was before.
You see I...
Never mind.
Good night.
How can I still be here when
all the young have gone to bed?
The motor's ready when you are.
When is Jarvis leaving?
I'm not sure.
It seems a poor return
for 40 years of service.
Maybe. But he was your father's man.
To him, you were always
the young master, never the Chief.
Which does not alter the fact
that now we must find someone else.
But you've already found him.
What do you mean?
Well, obviously the answer
to a thousand different questions
is to give the position to Branson.
Tom.
Well if he's the agent,
we can call him Branson again,
thank heaven.
That's a mad plan.
It's not.
Tom and Matthew can work
on the new ideas together.
They're the same age.
But what does he know of farming?
His grandfather was a farmer.
In a small way.
Which means he has more practical
experience than Jarvis ever had.
Think of the child.
You cannot want
your only granddaughter
to grow up in a garage
with that drunken gorilla?
Don't we owe this to Sybil?
I'll do it on one condition.
No, two.
First, Matthew must agree.
He will.
Second, you will both admit it
when you realise you were wrong.
Oh, well, that is an easy
caveat to accept
because I'm never wrong.
I don't need to tell you
that this is a criminal offence.
We hadn't done anything.
But you were hoping to do something
if Alfred hadn't come in.
It's not against the law to hope.
Don't you get clever with me
when you should be horsewhipped!
Do you have a defence?
Am I mistaken in any part of this?
Not really, Mr Carson.
As for a defence, what can I say?
I was... very drawn to him
and I'd got the impression
that he felt the same way.
I was wrong.
It seems an odd mistake to make.
When you're like me, Mr Carson,
you have to read the signs as best
you can because no one dares
speak out.
I do not wish to take a tour
of your revolting world.
No.
So, are you saying
that James is the innocent party
in all this?
Yes, Mr Carson, he is.
I will take time to consider.
We must first find out
what James intends to do.
He'd be within his rights
to report you to the police.
Although I'm quite sure
it won't come to that.
Will you give me your word
that nothing had happened?
I will, yes.
Right. Good night.
Mr Barrow looks very grim faced.
Never mind him.
Human nature's a funny business,
isn't it?
Now why didn't the poets
come to you, Mr Carson?
They'd have saved themselves
a lot of time and trouble.
What's this?
I hope you don't mind.
If you could all
form a group around the father.
Kieran. Right, Mama,
do you want to go next to Isobel?
It seems so strange
without Sybil here.
She's watching. I know.
I envy you. I wish I did.
Ever so slightly, thank you so much.
You want me to take on the running
of the estate? It's a big job.
Think of it as a Christening
present from Sybil.
It's a wonderful idea, Tom.
I'm ashamed it wasn't mine.
Perhaps one with
the grandfather holding the baby?
And maybe the great
grandmother with him?
And what about Father Dominic
who Christened her?
What's the matter, Robert?
Are you afraid you'll be converted
while you're not looking?
I'm to leave with no reference,
after working here for ten years?
Are you sure about Rose? Wouldn't
it be better if she stayed here?
No, no, no.
I'm quite looking forward to it.
Perhaps I'll run away.
Not this time.
Oh, my G...
I ought to report him to the police.
What?
I never wanted to push it this far.
I must hand in
my resignation at once.
Robert, the last time you made
an investment you ruined the family!
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.